<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>frw-find-retain-wow</title>
    <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow" />
    <updated>2018-03-29T12:14:32+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>abhishek rai</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Are there any guidelines from big B2B companies for their sales people on how to use social media to close more deals?</title>
        <author>
            <name>abhishek rai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/are-there-any-guidelines-from-big-b2b-companies-for-their-sales-people-on-how-to-use-social-media-to-close-more-deals/"/>
        <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/are-there-any-guidelines-from-big-b2b-companies-for-their-sales-people-on-how-to-use-social-media-to-close-more-deals/</id>
            <category term="socialmedia"/>
            <category term="sales"/>
            <category term="B2BSales"/>

        <updated>2018-03-29T11:53:28+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/media/posts/4/open-book-library-education-read-159621.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p><a href="http://qr.ae/TU1CF2"></a><a href="http://qr.ae/TU1CF2">Are there any guidelines from big B2B companies for their sales people on how to use social media to close more deals?</a></p>
<p>Sales is all about going prepared to your customer, rather prospective customer.</p>
<p>Social Media has opened a big tap for serious sales people, so that they can do methodical research on their prospective clients. This includes both the business, they are trying to pitch and the relevant person, who is conduit to that business.</p>
<p>Doing online research about the business on Social Media and then beefing that up with whatever information is available online for the relevant person, once can prepare a comprehensive dossier, which could act extremely handy during the sales presentation.</p>
<p>The dossier can be divided in to three parts:</p>
<p><strong>1. Questions to seek further details.</strong></p>
<p class="msg msg--info">List down questions which needs to be asked in order to gather complete details from the customer, in order to satisfactorily make a successful proposal. This would have details from what the company has done in the past, how that impacted it's revenue, what the company is trying to do current, who are it's present customers and how they fit into the total scheme of things with respect to the current proposal to be made, what is the future plan of the ocmpany and how adaptive one has to be able to make the proposal a sound long-term one.</p>
<p><strong>2. Arguements to support the sales pitch.</strong></p>
<p class="msg msg--info">Gather all the data points related with company which could help you bolster your sales pitch.</p>
<p><strong>3. Conversation inputs to increase confidence.</strong></p>
<p class="msg msg--info">It is important and essential that the salesman sounds prepared when she is talking. There are various tits and bits of information available online, which could help bolster her position, as she is conversing with the relevant representative of the customer company. There would be instances when the representative would be telling a piece of story, and you are able to complete the rest of it, because you have already done a methodical research ont he same, leading to a complete <strong>'WOW' </strong>moment for the representative. </p>
<p>While this research is done it is essential to omit everything which are <em>'professional non-essentials'</em> and could sound like, someone was <em>'snooping instead of researching'. </em>Eg: Personal opinions about products, politics, hobbies, friends etc.</p>
<p> </p>
<br>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How do I best structure my sales commissions/incentives?</title>
        <author>
            <name>abhishek rai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/how-do-i-best-structure-my-sales-commissionsincentives/"/>
        <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/how-do-i-best-structure-my-sales-commissionsincentives/</id>
            <category term="salesincentive"/>

        <updated>2018-03-28T07:20:24+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/media/posts/3/pexels-photo-462402.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p><a href="https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-best-structure-my-sales-commissions-incentives">How do I best structure my sales commissions/incentives?</a></p>
<p>There are many components to a <em>popular sales incentives plan </em>but the major component which most of them, if not all, fail to incorporate is <strong>'loyalty'</strong>.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><strong>For the same grade, a sales incentive plan should be higher for employees who have served the organisation longer.</strong> The absolute percentage increase could be low single digit only, but they definitely need to be more. This would differ with industry and market dynamics.</p>
<p>An employee who has served few years with organisation is far more valuable than someone who has just joined, for very obvious reasons.</p>
<p>Organisations show their respect towards a <strong>'loyal' </strong>employee in many different ways and sales incentives could be one of those way, and may be the perfect way to close the loop.</p>
<p>There are times when an outsider is recruited in the same grade/band with a higher compensation structure, compared to an existing employee who has put few years under his belt, due to several factors, one of which is the new employee's past pay.</p>
<p>While this could not be helped either by the existing employee or the organisation, the organisation has an opportunity here to show it's respect for the loyalty of the existing employee, by giving her a slight edge in sales incentives structure.</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><strong>Eg:</strong> <em>Within the same grade, if the incentive for fulfilling an annual target of revenue is 20% of gross  annual basic salary for a new employee, it could be 22% for the existing employee. The percentage increase would vary depending on the increasing years of service for an employee.</em></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>I&#x27;m the technical founder of a B2B SaaS startup. What is a good sales training course I can take to better understand software sales?</title>
        <author>
            <name>abhishek rai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/im-the-technical-founder-of-a-b2b-saas-startup-what-is-a-good-sales-training-course-i-can-take-to-better-understand-software-sales/"/>
        <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/im-the-technical-founder-of-a-b2b-saas-startup-what-is-a-good-sales-training-course-i-can-take-to-better-understand-software-sales/</id>
            <category term="Saas"/>
            <category term="SaaSStartup"/>
            <category term="B2BSales"/>

        <updated>2018-03-27T06:58:10+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/media/posts/2/pexels-photo-618158.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p><a href="https://www.quora.com/Im-the-technical-founder-of-a-B2B-SaaS-startup-What-is-a-good-sales-training-course-I-can-take-to-better-understand-software-sales">I'm the technical founder of a B2B SaaS startup. What is a good sales training course I can take to better understand software sales?</a></p>
<p>Let us try to resolve this question asked on Quora.</p>
<p>Let us ask another question in a little different manner to the gentleman who asked this question:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I'm a non-technical founder of a B2B Saas startup, how do I understand the intricasies of  code deployed at my company?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Well, the answer could be simple and a long one, most probably outlining a path towards learning programming and then slowly graduating on to more complex things.</p>
<p>In the similar vein, there is only one way to understand sales process, be it in any industry.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight ">Start selling...</p>
<p class="msg msg--info">The step to begin with would be :</p>
<ol>
<li>Do a research of your landscape, exiting solutions and competitors as well.</li>
<li>Make a list of probable prospects (companies) to be pitched of your innovative solution.</li>
<li>Find out the CXOs email address.</li>
<li>Write a personal and engaging copy with a good subject line, pitching your product to each of the prospect.</li>
<li>Wait for the reverts and their reactions.</li>
<li>Put the reverts received/not-recieved into three baskets:
<ol style="list-style-type: lower-roman;">
<li>RED: Reply not received. Re-tooling of the copy and subject line required through better research.</li>
<li>ORANGE: Not interested. More research and follow-up required.</li>
<li>GREEN: Interested. Secure a demo.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Go back to 1</li>
</ol>
<p>This way, you would receive a far greater understanding of the entire B2B sales process, than any course can deliver.</p>
<p>Once you have worked this way, for a couple of years, do look for an offline/online reputed course, which could compliment your practical experience of past two years.</p>
<p>Now, when you would enroll in a sales course, since you have practical experience, you could co-relate what is being taught, to what you have exprienced already and be able to connect the dots.</p>
<p>Most probably, you might not need the course any more...</p>
<p class="msg msg--success"><strong>PS:</strong> If I could help you more in any way, please feel free to reach out to me, via comment or email.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What is &#x27;Find, Retain, Wow&#x27;?</title>
        <author>
            <name>abhishek rai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/what-is-find-retain-wow/"/>
        <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/what-is-find-retain-wow/</id>
            <category term="startupsales"/>
            <category term="startup"/>
            <category term="sales"/>

        <updated>2018-03-27T06:57:54+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://therealmccoy.github.io/find-retain-wow/media/posts/1/pexels-photo-751073.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>During last decade or so, the techonlogical barrier to start a startup has considerably come down. No need to have your own servers, set-up data-centers, hosting etc.</p>
<p>And then came social media and this <em>'viral'</em> pehomenon, and suddenly one could be a <em>'overnight success'</em>.</p>
<p>But over a period of time, it is becoming more and more difficult for a new startup to get customers. The reason is simple, the things which made starting a startup simple, has now given the customer a big basket of choices to choose from. Not mentioning, ever decreasing short attention time.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><strong>Things have come to such pass that 'attention' has become the biggest obstacle of building a successful startup, ie getting the attention of your customer! </strong></p>
<p>Perhaps it could be even said that the resources in terms of both time and money which were earlier deployed for just starting a startup, are now being deployed to get the first bunch of customers. In some cases, many folds over.</p>
<p>The reason now for which the startups are not succeeding is not 'not having the technology' but 'not having the customers'.</p>
<p>A few decades back, it was said about the customers that '<em>If you build for them, they will come to you' </em>because the entire <em>'building' </em>stuff was the challenge.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight ">Now the above statement could be very well rephrased as <em>'If you build for them, you still have to find them'</em></p>
<p>Find, Retain, Wow aims to be that place, which could solve your queries regarding how to find the first bunch of customers for your startup, what you are doing right and what you are doing not so right in your startup sales and from there on we move to how to retain your customers in this ultra-competitive environment and then to keep them for the life-time, by delivering a 'wow' experience!</p>
<p>You can email your specific queries or post comments on this blog's post regarding the same.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><strong>'<em>Amat Victoria Curam</em>' which means 'Victory loves preparation.</strong></p>
<p>Find, Retain, Wow helps you prepare for your startup victory by guiding you through your company's entire sales set-up and process.</p>
<p><strong>Saddle up, lock and load!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
